Sophie Berger

BSc in Computer Science and Masters of Management student at UBC Android, iOS, Web and AR experience

Microsoft Imagine cup Regional Finalist, and Hackathon winner

+1 (236) 862-3848 berger.m.sophie@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/sophiemb github.com/SophieMBerger sophiemberger.github.io/

"Strength Insight Report" (from Gallup / CliftonStrengths): Achiever, Strategic, Learner, Futuristic, Focus

Skills

Proficient: Java (6 yrs), Swift (3 yrs), Firebase, ARKit **Familiar:** C, C++, Kotlin, Python, JavaScript, React, Unity, Tensorflow, HTML, CSS

Experience

Undergraduate Researcher 03/ 2020 – 08/ 2020 USRA/SURE internship through UBC

- AR-based instructions for elderly users
- Supervised by Prof. Dongwook Yoon

Equity-owner of "Mindset" startup 10/2019 – Present iOS Expert/equity-owner

- <u>Front-end development</u> on dementia screening iOS app using **Swift**
- Analyzed iOS UI/UX compatibility
- Wrote a tech-specification document for outsourced development

Tailored Apps

05/2019 - 07/2019

iOS Software Developer Intern

- <u>Implemented</u> **Firebase** authentication/Cloud Functions
- Added AR and object recognition using ARKit
- Parsed Json from a database for in-app deep links
- <u>Serialized data</u> using the Codable protocol
- Localized using a Fastlane Google-Sheet plugin
- Helped CTO <u>estimate the feasibility/pricing</u> of a Machine Learning project

Competitions

Microsoft Imagine Cup Regional Finalist 05/ 2019
Americas regional final
(bit.ly/imaginenekotap)

- In top 12 teams out 30,000+ participants in the Americas
- Presented at the Microsoft Build conference
- Same as "nekoTap" project below

1st place at nwHacks with "nekoTap" 01/ 2019 Western Canada's largest Hackathon (1000+ participants)

(devpost.com/software/nekotap)

- Android app for improved drug adherence using NFC technology to receive tailored drug information
- <u>Designed</u> animations using Lottie library and <u>implemented</u> Android front-end using **Java** to increase usability/accessibility within the app

Education

BSc in Computer Science 09/ 2018 – 12/ 2022 + Master of Management: 09/ 2018 – 12/ 2023

- Average = 83.9%, Dean's honor list
- Relevant courses: Models of computation,
 Software construction, Introduction to Computer
 Systems, Basic Algorithms and Data Structures

"Java Foundations Certified Junior 03/ 2017 Associate" - Awarded by Oracle University

Selected projects

Soil TopARgraphy

10/2018 - 09/2019

Android & Unity Developer for UBC Launchpad (eml.ubc.ca/projects/soil-topargraphy/)

- <u>Created</u> an AR app for Dr. Maja Krzic's soil science class at UBC
- <u>Created</u> Android front-end using Kotlin and Java
- Added UI features to custom AR map in Unity
- Offers more engaging education to 250+ students
- <u>Utilized</u> Google Maps Android SDK for location
- <u>Presented</u> at UBC "Multidisciplinary Undergraduate Research Conference"

Google NIMA in TensorFlow Lite

07/2019

Proof of concept for TailoredApps (bit.ly/TFLiteGoogleNIMA)

- <u>Converted</u> existing "<u>Neural Image Assessment</u>" models to <u>TensorFlow Lite</u> models using <u>Python</u>
- <u>Developed</u> an iOS project to <u>rank images</u> and determine the "best" overall image using **Swift**

Community Involvement

Microsoft Student Partner (MSP) 09/2019 - Present Microsoft

• Represented Microsoft and educated about technology on social media/my university campus

nwPlus Engagement Coordinator 04/ 2020- Present nwPlus

- <u>Organizing</u> multiple hackathons, including Western Canada's largest hackathon (nwHacks)
- <u>Collaborating</u> with universities, industries and hackathon attendees